Guide to the Polly Shackleton papers, 1894-1997 MS2031
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Polly Shackleton papers
1894-1997
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Shackleton, Polly
MS2031
180 Linear Feet This extent is an approximation as box type data is unknown for a large portion of the collection.
Collection contains correspondence, memorandums, newsletters, speeches, news releases, public statements, news clippings, newspapers, events brochures, pamphlets, posters, buttons and pins, photographs, cassette tapes, plaques and awards, hats, scarves, a 44 star flag, expired passports, membership and identification cards, hats, and buttons and pins documenting Polly Shackleton's (1910-1997) career as a politician and social activist in Washington, D.C. during the second half of the twentieth century.
Restrictions on Access
The collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Polly Shackleton donated her papers to the Gelman Library in 1987, with further accretions occurring over the next twelve years. In 1991, Polly Shackleton donated her Oral History to the Gelman Library, and in 1992, she also donated additional papers to the library. After her death in 1997, a donation of materials was made to the Historical Society of Washington, D.C., which were then transferred to the Gelman Library in 1999.
Historical or Biographical Note
Polly Shackleton (1910-1997) was a politician and social activist in Washington, D.C. during the second half of the twentieth century. She came to Washington in 1939, after a brief enrollment at the New School of Social Research in New York and working on FDR's campaign during the 1930's. Polly Shackleton's professional endeavors prior to her work with District of Columbia politics included an editorial position of Who's Who in American Art and the American Art Annual, work with the Office of War Information as an information specialist and researcher during World War II, and an eleven year position with the American Institute of Architects from 1951 to 1962.
Polly Shackleton became involved in the politics of Washington, D.C. during the 1950's while working on Adlai Stevenson's Democratic campaign. After Stevenson won the Democratic nomination, Shackleton became both a Democratic Central Committee member and an alternate Democratic National Committeewoman. In 1956, she was a delegate to the Democratic National Convention and served on the platform committee. Polly Shackleton remained at the forefront of local political affairs in the District of Columbia, and in 1967 she was appointed to the first .DC Council by President Johnson. As one of the first appointed council members of D.C., some of her responsibilities included serving on various council committees, particularly ones concerned with health and welfare, citizen's rights, and childcare. Though not reappointed to the following council term, Polly Shackleton won a seat on the District's first elected council in 1974. She was reelected to that seat twice, once in 1978 and a second time in 1982. She served on the elected DC Council until 1986 when she retired from public office. While serving on the city's elected council, Polly Shackleton was responsible for the passing of approximately 60 pieces of legislation that eventually became District law through her sponsorship and co-sponsorship.
Polly Shackleton's dedication to the social and political conditions in Washington D.C. is made evident through her life and work. She was a major advocate for District Home Rule and National Representation in Congress, lobbying for these causes throughout her career. Most of her greatest social efforts involved improving conditions for and protecting the existing rights of those whose interests were most often overlooked by the government, such as the poor, children, and the elderly and infirm. She fought against transportation legislation that sought to build highways through the District, and would result in the displacement of many residents in low-income areas. She was an advocate of the METRO system, taking an active role in its planning and development, and also sought to develop bicycle paths and routes throughout the city. She was involved with First Lady Johnson's District beautification efforts, and much of the collection includes information on Project Pride, a city-wide summer program that aimed to provide District youth with activities that would help build skills and foster a sense of community within neighborhoods while working to beautify certain areas of Washington, D.C. Polly Shackleton also took a stand to improve health care for the young and old alike, securing licensing standards for nursing homes, building better nursing facilities for the infirm, and advocating for better services and management in D.C. General Hospital.
At the time of her death, Polly Shackleton was referred to as a bridge between her predominately white higher income constituents in Ward 3 and the rest of the city's residents whose interests she fought for throughout her career. She was remembered for the many social and political improvement efforts she undertook as a politician, and also for the individualized attention she paid to those who came to her for help; the collection contains numerous thank you letters from District residents who had turned to Polly Shackleton with a problem and found their needs had been met. She outlived her husband, Robert Shackleton, by nine years, and lived long enough to see the fruits of her social and political labor.
Polly Shackleton was born in Brookline, Massachusetts.
Collection Scope and Content
This collection contains correspondence, memorandums, newsletters, speeches, news releases, public statements, news clippings, newspapers, events brochures, pamphlets, posters, buttons and pins, photographs, cassette tapes, plaques and awards, hats, scarves, a 44 star flag, expired passports, membership and identification cards, hats, and buttons and pins. The collection contains materials that date from 1900 ca. -97 with the bulk of the material dating from 1960-1979.
The materials tell the story of Polly Shackleton's political and civic activities in Washington D.C. politics. The collection documents Polly Shackleton's role in the development of the City Council of the District of Columbia and the D.C. City Council, the appointed and elected governing bodies of the District that were implemented in the late 1960's and early 1970's. The collection also provides information related to the various civic and voluntary activities Polly Shackleton was involved in as a member of numerous social and political organizations. Much of her work was dedicated to improving social conditions for the people of Washington D.C., and touched on areas such as family and child services, hospital services, services for the infirm and elderly, housing, transportation, and securing political representation for the District and its residents.
Collection Organization
Organized into 10 series: General records; News clippings; Photographs; Oversized; Scrapbooks; Ephemera, Oral history, Aphabetical files, Office files, and Subject, chronological, and correspondence files.
Scrapbooks; Home rule; Child welfare; Photographs; Politics and government; Transportation; Housing; Medical care; Politicians; City councils; Washington (D.C.); Nursing homes; Shackleton, Polly; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano); Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines); District of Columbia. City Council
- General records, 1915-1995; MS2031 Series 1; 9 Linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains correspondence, pamphlets, press releases, speeches and public statements, memorandums, and other items related to the various public and private projects Polly Shackleton was involved in during her political career. The material is dated rom 1915-95. Organizations, groups, and services that Shackleton was involved with include beautification projects, City Council of the District of Columbia, Democratic Central Committee, Democratic National Committee, District of Columbia Hospital Association, Family and Child Services, Family and Child Services, Health and Welfare Council of the National Capital Area, Health Planning Advisory Committee, METRO, National Capital Area Day Care Association, Project Pride, Southeast Neighborhood House, Society for a More Beautiful Capital, Washington Housing Association, Washington Planning and Housing Association, Women's National Democratic Club.
  - Biographical Information, 1941-1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Campaign Records, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Candidate for City Council, Ward Three, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Cartoon Drawing, "Polly For President", undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Certificate of Appreciation, My Sister's Place, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Democratic Central Committee, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Democratic National Committee, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Donation of Personal Papers to Gelman Library, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Employment Records, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Events, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Glover Park Citizens Association, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Handwritten Notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Letterheads, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Lil' Abner Comic Book, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Model Cities Senior Center, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Personal Papers - Financial, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Personal Papers, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Public Statements, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Resume, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Sample Ballot, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Washington's Salute to President Johnson, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - White House Notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Senate Resolution - S.J. Res. 32, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Senate Bill - S. 1513, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Employment Records, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Seiren I Orkenen, Circa 1940 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - House of Representatives Act - H.R. 5558, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Senate Bill - S. 1445, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Senate Bill - S. 1945, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Employment Records, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Public Law 534 - 77th Congress, Chapter 265 - 2nd Session, H.R. 5075, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Employment Records, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Employment Records, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Employment Records, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Outpost Report, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Employment Records, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Financial Records, 1946-1948 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Employment Records, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Employment Records, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Democratic National Committee, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Democratic National Committee, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Events, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Memorandums, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Women's National Democratic Club, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Democratic National Committee, Office of Women's Activities, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Family and Child Services, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Sam Rayburn Testimonial Dinner, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - A Directory of Newspapers, Radios, and TV, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Democratic National Committee, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Events, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Family and Child Services, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Jenny for President, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Public Relations, Circa 1956 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Stevenson Campaign, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Democratic National Committee, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Events, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - AIA Journal, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Democratic Central Committee, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Democratic National Committee, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Family and Child Services, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Health and Welfare Council, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - United Community Services, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Women's National Democratic Club, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - AIA Journal, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Democratic National Committee, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Health and Welfare Council of the National Capital Area, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Washington Housing Association, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Adlai Stevenson Campaign, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Democratic National Committee, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Democratic Women, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Hubert Humphrey Campaign, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - John F. Kennedy Campaign, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Democratic National Committee, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Family and Child Services, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - John F. Kennedy Inauguration, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Nomination of Frank D. Reeves, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Press Releases, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Washington Housing Association, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - A Citizen's Study of Public Education in Philadelphia, Part A, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Democratic National Committee, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Excerpt from Department of State Newsletter, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    General note
    "Mrs. Louchheim Advocates: Cooperation Among Free World Women for Greater Social Progress"
  - Memorandum, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Re: Juvenile Court Decision
  - Miscellaneous, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Press Releases, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Public Statements, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Washington Planning and Housing Association, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Amendment by Senators Ribicoff-Case-Clark-Humphrey for Aid to Children of Unemployed Parents, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Broadcast Editorial on Highways and Rapid Transit, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Building Research Institute, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Citizens Council for the District of Columbia, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Current Membership, Agencies, Boards, Commissions, Committees, Councils, undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Government of the District of Columbia, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Democratic National Committee, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Events, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Fiscal Year 1964 Budget, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Foreign Student Service Council, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Health and Welfare Council, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Inaugural Anniversary Dinner, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - National Capital Housing Authority, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Population Dilemma, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Report by The George Washington University, American Assembly
  - Public Statements, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Searching Homes of Welfare Recipients, the Issues Under the Social Security Act, The Social Service Review, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Southeast Neighborhood House, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - The D.C. Democrat, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Transit, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Washington Planning and Housing Association, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Women's National Democratic Club, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - 1964 Election (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Ad Hoc Committee on the Housing Crisis, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Citizens for Johnson-Humphrey, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Democratic Campaign, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Democratic Central Committee, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Democratic National Committee, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Democratic National Committee - Office of Women's Activities, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Democratic National Convention I, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Democratic National Convention II, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Events, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Excerpts from Speeches by Mrs. Lyndon B. Johnson as First Lady, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Fiscal Year 1965 Budget, 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Friendship Citizens Association, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Goldwater Fact Sheets, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Health and Welfare Council, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Hospitality House, Inc., 1964 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Interdepartmental Committee and Citizens' Advisory Council on the Status of Women, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - National Citizens for Johnson and Humphrey, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Negro Student Fund, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Poverty in the United States; Committee on Education and Labor, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    House of Representatives, Eighty-Eighth Congress, Second Session
  - Press Releases, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Public Statements, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Southeast Neighborhood House, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - State of the Union Message By the President to a Joint Session of the Congress, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Student Non-Violent Coordinating Committee, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - The D.C. Democrat, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - United Democrats for Johnson, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Valley Green Project, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - War on Poverty/Juvenile Delinquency, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Washington Planning and Housing Association, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Women's National Democratic Club, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Youth Involvement on the Democratic Campaign, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - A Regional Conference On Civil Rights for Women of Conscience from Delaware, Maryland, and the District of Columbia, 1965 April 05-April 06 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    Sponsored by the National Council of Women of the United States
  - A Regional Conference On Civil Rights for Women of Conscience from Delaware, Maryland, and the District of Columbia; Sponsored by the National Council of Women of the United States, 1965 April 05-April 06 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Adams-Morgan News, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Beautification Kit - Consumer Services of the U.S. Department of Agriculture, Circa 1965 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Children in D.C., 1965 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Citizens for Johnson and Humphrey, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Committee for a More Beautiful Capital, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Committee for the Preservation of Georgetown, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Craft, Kathryn, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - D.C. Coalition of Conscience, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Democratic Central Committee, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Democratic National Committee - Democratic Women I, 1965 January-June (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Democratic National Committee - Democratic Women II, 1965 July-December (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - District of Columbia Democratic Organization, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Events, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Highway Construction, Circa 1965 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Inauguration of Lyndon B. Johnson, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - International Voluntary Services, Inc.; Agents of Change in Rural Development, Education, Agriculture, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - March from Selma to Montgomery, Alabama, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Memorandum to: Polly Shackleton, 1965 November 12 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - National Capital Area Child Day Care Association, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - National Capital Landscape, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Public Statements, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Report to the President and the President's Response, White House Conference on Natural Beauty, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Report to the President from the First Lady's Committee for a More Beautiful Capital, Circa 1965 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Resume, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Rustin, Bayard, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Sale and Distribution of Alcohol, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Society For a More Beautiful Capital, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - State of the Union Message by the President to a Joint Session of the Congress, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Subcommittee on Enforcement of the Housing Code, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - The D.C. Democrat, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - The Reston Letter, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Urban Planning - Adams Morgan, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - U.S. Department of Labor - Women's Bureau, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Washington Urban League, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Women's National Democratic Club, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - American Association of Nurserymen, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Beautification - Second Precinct Police Station, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Beautification, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Campaign Conference for Democratic Women, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - City Planning and Suit, Circa 1966 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Committee of 100 on the Federal City, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Education, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Events, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Health and Welfare Council, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Hyde School Forum, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Interdependence of our Central City and the Suburbs In Providing A Viable Human Environment, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Legislative Newsletter, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Memorandum, 1966 December 10 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    To: Mrs. Louise Odione; Re: Greenhouse Installation - Public Schools
  - National Arboretum Children's Field Trip, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - National Capital Area Day Care Association, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - National Capital Planning Commission, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Omnibus Crime Bill (H.R. 5688), 1966 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Project Pride - Gardening Project at the C. Melvin Shape Heath School, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Project Pride - New Clipping, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Project Pride - Purchase of Red Squill Rodenticides, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Project Pride I, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Project Pride II, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Project Pride III, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Public Statements, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Society for a More Beautiful National Capital, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Testimony of Theodore Prahinski, Federation of Civic Associations, Circa 1966 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Commission I, 1963-1966 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Commission II, 1965-1966 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Women Doers, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Women's National Democratic Club, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Beautification Programs Financial Records, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Capital East Steering Committee, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - City Council Files, Budget Justification, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - City Council Files, Congressional Committees, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - City Council Files, Council Members, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - City Council Files, Council Staff, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - City Council Files, Organization, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - City Council Files, Table of Contents, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence I, 1967 January-June (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence II, 1967 July-September (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence III, 1967 October-December (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Democratic Central Committee, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Events, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Harris, Ruth Bates, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Holiday Magazine Beautification Award, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - NAACP, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Neighborhood Problems: Some questions (an outline), 1967 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Master's Thesis, "Political Parties in the District of Columbia", 1967 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    author: Vary Taylor Coates
  - Press Releases, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 17)